This story is fiction. The names of people,
places and groups are imaginary.
Obey traffic rules and drive safely.
Initial
Raise up your hands takaku
Raise up your hands 高く[Everybody gonna tell you I can't stop]
(Everybody now te wo agero saa)
Tsukame brand new tomorrow
掴め Brand new tomorrow[You don't stop]
(You don't stop)
Kaze no naka de jibun wo shiru
風の中で 自分を知る ずっと最高のDreamだろう
Zutto zekkei no dream darou
(Let's go)
Oh[Let's go] Oh[Let's go]
Oh
Oh (Let's go)
Oh, raise up your hands now.
Oh raise up you can't stop
Ikiteru dake de marumouke nara ganbarouze marugoto ittennbari
生きてるだけで何やろうかな
Gamble on 迫る鼓動にテンバリ
同じMission 同じ一生
Onaji mission, onaji isshou
Dondake yume atsuika ga shobu darou
どんだけ夢熱いかが勝負だろ
Escalator nashi no eien
Escalator 無しの永遠
Ashi koshi kitae reruze yeah, yeah
足腰鍛え Let's begin yeah
Douse noboru kaidan
どうせのぼる階段
Kokoro kocchi ni customize shichaeba ii
心こっちにCustomizeしちゃえばいい
Kezurarete sugiru mainichi
削られて 過ぎる毎日[But you know]
Kezurarete sugiru mainichi (But you know ?)
Semegai no aru game to warai tobashite
攻めがいのあるGameと 笑い飛ばして
Let's see how fast you can do it
Let's see how fast you can do it.
Raise up your hands zutto
Raise up your hands ずっと[Everybody gonna tell you I can't stop]
(Everybody now te wo agero saa)
Hashire sleepless challenger
走れ Sleepless challenger [You don't stop]
(You don't stop)
Ima ni ikiru riyuu sagasu
今に生きる 理由を探す
夢尽きないQuest
Yume tsukinai quest
(Let's go)
Oh[Let's go] Oh[Let's go]
Oh
Oh (Let's go)
Oh, raise up your hands now.
Oh raise up you can't stop
なるほどな
I see. No wonder the left rear felt light.
これじゃ左リアが抜けるわけだぜ
左コーナーで踏ん張りが利かずに　ドカンとオーバーが出やがったな
I couldn't maintain grip in the left corner,
and massively over-steered.
大宮さん
Omiya...
It can't be helped.
仕方ないさ　勝敗は時の運だし
Luck is a part of the game, and I couldn't
have been more motivated today.
今日の俺は乗れてたと思う
つくづく自分の走りのルーツは　峠なんだと思い知らされてる
I've come to realize that the root of
my driving lies in the mountain passes.
サーキットのレースでは多分味わえないだろう
You can't experience the sensation
of your head going blank on the circuit.
頭の中が真っ白になる　あの痺れる感じは
本当の勝負ができたことが嬉しいんだ
I'm happy that I could fight a real battle,
because it doesn't happen very often in life.
人生の中でもそう何回もあるわけじゃないからな
Man, I didn't expect Omiya
to lose to that Eight-Six kid.
いや　それにしても
あの大宮がハチロクのボーヤに負けるとは　誤算でしたな
He's quite mysterious.
あれはなかなか不気味な存在ですわ
Too bad he didn't go for a time trial.
タイムトライアルをしてくれへんかったのは残念でしたな
By learning his actual time, we could
have analyzed his car's fighting potential...
時計の数字を聞けば一発でクルマの戦闘力が分析できるうえに
...and figured out the kid's driving skills.
あのボーヤのドライバーとしてのポテンシャルも 把握できたんとちゃいますか
敵もバカじゃないってことだ
Our opponent isn't stupid.
Don't underestimate Takahashi Ryosuke.
高橋涼介という男を甘く見るなよ
Contact the guys scattered along
the course. We're heading home.
コースの彼方此方に散らばっている仲間にも連絡してくれ
俺達も撤収だ
Did you hear who won, Kogashiwa ?
聞いたか　小柏　どっちが勝ったのか
もちろん聞いています
Of course I did.
We should be happy,
because we get our chance.
歓迎すべきことじゃないですかね
俺達にお鉢が回ってくるわけだから
I guess you can say that.
そうとも言えるだな
俺はプロジェクトDの藤原拓海にちょっとした借りがありましてね
I have to pay back
Fujiwara Takumi of Project D.
いろは坂での借りは箱根で返しますよ
In Kanagawa, I'll get revenge for
my humiliation on the Iroha Slopes.
Fated Revenge Battle
We've been waiting for you !
いよっ　待ってました
エース登場
Here comes the Ace !
えっ　いや　あの
Well...ummm...
それでは　わたくし　リポーターのイツキが めでたく神奈川初戦を勝利した
Well then, let me, reporter Itsuki, interview Project D's
Fujiwara Takumi, who won his first battle in Kanagawa.
プロジェクトDの藤原拓海選手に聞いてみたいと思います
いいよー　そういうのは
Hey, I don't like that kind of thing.
Well, Mr. Fujiwara,
tell us what's on your mind.
それでは藤原さん　率直に今の気持ちをお聞かせください
ハイオク満タン　現金で
A full tank of high octane gas for cash.
バカッ　つまんねーんだよ
You moron ! So boring !
いつもテンション低いっつーか　ノリが悪いっつーか
How can you keep your
tension so low all the time ?
だって　俺がガソリン入れに来てんだぜ　しょうがないじゃん
But I just came here for gas.
It can't be helped.
ったくな　そんな言で次大丈夫なのか
Geez, are you ready for the next battle ?
拓海　神奈川の第二戦はいつなんだ
Takumi, when is the second match in Kanagawa ?
一周明けて　再来週です
The week after next.
We've decided to have
an interval before each race.
今回から毎回インターバル入れることになったんで
それじゃ　次の週末はちょっとゆっくりできるじゃん
That means you can
relax a bit next weekend.
More or less.
まぁな
遠いけど 一回ぐらいはプロジェクトDの　っいや　拓海の応援に行かないとな
It's a little far, but we've
got to see Project D...
...I mean Takumi race at least once.
おっ　いいね　どうせなら一泊して前日のプラクティスから見たいなー
Good idea. If we can, I want to stay overnight so
we can watch their practice the day before the race.
昼間は箱根の観光スポット回ったり　温泉入ったり
We can visit Hakone's tourist spots and
go to a hot spring during the day time.
温泉っすか　池谷先輩　温泉で混浴　けー！
Hot spring, you said, Iketani ?!
Bathing in a unisex hot spring ?!
Not all hot springs are unisex.
混浴とは限らねぇだろう
男の夢っすよ　夢
That's every man's dream. Just a dream.
Ummm...
あのっ あぁ 来るんなら早めに来たほうがいいですよ
If you're coming, the sooner the better.
If we lose, there'll be no other chance.
負けたらその時点で終わっちゃうんだから
オイオイ　縁起でもないこと言うなよ
Hey, don't jinx yourself.
勝ち続けてくれよー
Make sure you keep winning.
ったくー
Geez...
はい　松本です
Hello, this is Matsumoto.
What's the matter, Ryosuke ?
どうしたんです　涼介さん
Actually, I have a favor to ask of you.
実は　お前の腕を見込んで　頼みたいことがある
I'll do anything. Do you want a
super charger in the Eight-Six ?
何でもやりますよ
ハチロクにスーパーチャージャーを乗せるんですか
No, that's not it.
いや　そうじゃない
What, the FC ?
えっ　FCを
あぁ
Yeah.
なぜあのクルマを
But why your car ?
I can't tell you yet, but
something is bothering me.
今はまだ何とも言えないんだ
でもちょっと気がかりなことがあってな
このことはプロジェクトDとは別件だから
I see.
This is a separate matter from Project D,
so keep this between us for now.
当分の間　俺とお前だけの話にしておいてくれ
頼んだぞ
I'm counting on you.
Okay.
分かりました
サイドワインダーというチームに北条豪がいる限り
He will eventually show up, so long as
Hojo Gou is with the Sidewinder team...
必ずどこかであの人が出てくるだろう
俺には分かる それは避けられない宿命だ
I'm sure of it.
It's an unavoidable fate.
I can't run away from it...
逃げるわけには行かないだろうな
プロジェクトDのリーダーとしてじゃなく
...not because I'm the leader of Project D, but
because I'm a street racer, Takahashi Ryosuke.
一人の走り屋　高橋涼介として
けじめを付ける時なのかもしれない
Maybe it's time to put an end to...
香織さん
Kaori...
へぇー　拓海君　今度の日曜お休みなの
What ? You're off next weekend ?
Yeah, sort of.
うーん　まぁー
本当　本当　本当
Really ? For sure ?
Then let's go to the beach, the beach !
じゃー　海行こうよ　海
あっ　でも泊まりとかは無理
But no overnight stay,
not even coming home late.
帰りがあんまり遅いのも無理
っいいよ　その分　朝早く出ればいいんだから
That's fine. We just have to
leave early in the morning.
だよね　じゃー　本当に行けるんだ　海
You're so right. So we can go
to the beach for real then ?
海かー　随分行ってないなー
The beach...I haven't been
to one for a long time.
I bet there are tons of hot gals there.
エロイギャルが沢山いるんだろうな
俺も見たいな　ギャルの水着
I want to see gals in bathing suits.
Nobody says "gal" any more.
ギャルは死語だろう
I've been bothered by something for a long time.
俺はさ　昔から不思議に思っていたことなんだけどさー
Like there was a time when it was perfectly
okay for school girls to walk around the city...
例えば　女子高生ってだけでさ
パンツすれすれの短い制服で当たり前のように街を歩いてた時代があったじゃん
...wearing a uniform with a mini-skirt
that kept flashing their panties.
あった　あった　っていうか　今でもいますよ　そういうの
Yes, there was.
Actually, some still do even today.
よく考えてみれば　あれって異常なことだ
If you think about it,
that's really abnormal.
Even if they're ugly or have thick legs,
their skirts are way too revealing.
ブスだろうが　足が太かろうが 皆すれすれなんだぜ
On top of that, nobody thought it was strange.
おまけに誰もそれを変だと思わない
It must be some sort of mass hysteria.
あれは一種の集団ヒステリーみたいなものだったなー
それは　まぁ　一理ある
I guess you have a point.
それと同じことが 夏の海やプールで起こってしまうんだよ
The same thing happens at the
pool or on the beach in summer.
Personally, girls in bathing
suits are erotic and sexy.
女の子の水着なんて　俺に言わせりゃ　裸よりエロイし　恥ずかしい
Oh, really...
そっ　そうかー
しかも太陽燦燦と降り注ぐ屋外なのに
Besides that, how come these creatures called women
aren't embarrassed by such a look in broad daylight ?
あんな恥ずかしい格好で
なぜ平気なんだ　女という生き物は
そりゃ　だって　みんなそうだから
Well, maybe because
everyone else does the same ?
They're only supposed to appear like that to
a special someone in a dark private room !
暗い部屋の中で 特別な相手にしかあんな格好見せちゃいかんだろう
全く同感っす　池谷先輩
I feel the same way, Iketani !
っおおー　お前は分かってくれるか
You do understand, huh ?
In short, they're just jealous.
要するに　羨ましいだけだろう
出家でもするか　こんなエロイ世の中はいやだ
Maybe I should become a priest.
I hate this erotic world.
そうっすよね
You're right.
ごめんね
I'm sorry.
I always ask you to come to Saitama.
だって　いつも拓海君に埼玉まで来てもらって
You don't have to worry about that.
そんなことを気にしないでいいよ
でも　すごいね　私達
This's incredible for us. Before, we
only chatted at a family restaurant.
いままでファミレスで話すだけのデートだったのに
But we've been together since this
morning and come all the way here.
朝から一緒だし　こんな遠くにも来ちゃったし
何もかも新記録だねー
Everything is a new record.
だよな　何か現実じゃないみたいな気がするよ
Right. This almost feels unreal.
拓海の奴さー　最近何気にいい顔するようになったよなー
Takumi looks pretty sharp these days.
っおお　確かにな
Yeah, you're right.
He looks more manly.
前より男らしい顔になってきてる
昔はポーカーフェイスっていうより
He used to wear a poker face,
or more like an emotionless kid.
あんまり表情なくて　まだ子供って感じだったもんなー
やっば自信だと思うよ
I think it's because of his confidence.
プロジェクトDのエースを見事に勤め上げてるんだから
He's fulfilling his duty
as an ace of Project D.
高橋涼介の期待にきちんと応えて　結果出してますもんね
He meets Takahashi Ryosuke's
expectations and gets results.
He did grow up.
There's no way we can do the same.
本当成長したな　俺達には考えられないもん
しんどいかもしれないけど　物凄く幸せなことだろうな
It must be tough, but also very happy...
About what ?
何が
To be a member of Project D.
プロジェクトDの一員でいられることがだよ
チームを構成して
I'm envious because he can maintain
the tension of aiming for one goal...
力を合わせて　一つの目的に向かって進んで行くテンションが羨ましい
...by acting as part of a team
and joining forces with others.
誰にでもできる体験じゃないし
It's not something everyone can do.
He shines so brightly to those
who spend their days aimlessly.
のんべんだらりと生きている人間には眩しく見えちまうよな
あの野郎　エアコンの効きがいいからって
That brat took my Imp
because the A/C works better.
俺のインプ乗って行きやがって
Thank you, Takumi. I still have
plenty of time before my curfew.
ありがとう　拓海君　門限には余裕だったね
Good thing we didn't get
caught in a traffic jam.
よかったよ　渋滞に巻き込まれなくて
Well then...
じゃ
帰り気を付けてね　拓海君
Be careful on the way home, Takumi.
You too, Mika-chan.
美佳ちゃんもね
っあー　拓海君　ちょっと待って
Oh, Takumi, wait.
あのね　あのね　美佳ちゃんじゃなくて　美佳って呼び捨てにしてみて
Umm, you see...
Can you just call me "Mika,"
instead of "Mika-chan" ?
ねー
Go ahead.
うん　美佳
Mika.
へへ　いい感じ
Nice.
Call me that from now on. Bye.
これからはそう呼んでね　じゃね
想像してたより　いいバランスだ
The balance is better than expected.
Takahashi Ryosuke is quite a guy.
大したもんだ　高橋涼介ってのは
短期間でこれだけの足を仕上げるセンス　俺にはないね
I don't have the ability to refine the suspension
settings like this in such a short period of time.
It can go really further with this...
これなら　かなりの所まで行ける
...but probably not until the final step.
だが恐らく　最後までは無理だ
しょうがねぇ　準備だけはしておくか
It can't be helped.
I guess I have to be prepared.
俺があいつにしてやれることがこれが最後になるかな
That'll be the last thing I can do for Takumi.
いいや　何かすげーな
Man, this is awesome.
So it was a roll cage when you
said something about safety stuff.
保安部品を同工って言ってたのは ロールケージのことか
やっぱ　雰囲気がガラッと変わるよ
The mood is totally different.
I feel strange. It's like
sitting inside a solid box.
頑丈な箱の中に座ってるみたいな
不思議な感じですよ
ここんとこ何かと急ピッチだよな
The pace of modification seems faster lately.
プロジェクトDのファクトリーも 激戦地神奈川に挑む意気ごみを感じさせるよ
I can tell that the Project D factory is devoted to the races in Kanagawa.
Finally, the second race in Kanagawa.
いよいよ神奈川第二戦か
場所は何処なんだ　拓海
So where is it going to be held, Takumi ?
Oh, I heard it's going to be Hakone.
箱根って聞いてるけど
よくなったろ
Better ?
ばっちりだね
Right on. Your adjustment
perfectly matches this course.
このコースには最高なアジャストだ
I can't lose to amateurs.
素人集団に負けるわけにはいかねからな
何つってもレーシングチームカタギリの主戦場は
That said, Racing Team Katagiri's main
battlefield is the circuit, not the public roads.
公道なんかじゃなくて　サーキットだからな
心配要りません
Don't worry. It's impossible
to find a reason for me to lose.
どう考えても負ける理由を探すほうが難しい
I'll put an end to the glory
of Fujiwara Takumi, I mean...
今度こそ引導を渡すぜ
藤原拓海　いいや
秋名のハチロクに
...of Akina's Eight-Six.
あいつらの強さの理由はよくも悪くもガキだからですよ
Their strength lies more
or less in their immaturity.
ガキか
Immaturity, huh ?
Yes. If you drive on the circuit, you get used to safety, and grow fearful of mountain passes.
ええ
サーキットばかり走っていると
安全になれてしまって 峠が怖くなる
It's natural because there are no escape zones,
and you don't know what's beyond the blind corner.
そうりゃそうでしょう
エスケープゾーンはないし
ブラインドコーナーの先に何があるのか分からないんだから
It's not a game for rational adults to play.
分別のある大人のやることじゃないですね
That's exactly what
I want to tell you, Kogashiwa.
そっくりそのまま お前に言ってやりたいよ小柏
それが分かっていながら
Even though you know that, you're
still going to fight this ridiculous battle.
こんなバカなバトルをしようってんだからな
That means I'm still
immature to a certain extent.
ぎりぎりまだ俺もガキってことです
これは俺の卒業式なんだ
This is my graduation ceremony.
あと一年たったら 俺もたぶん峠が怖くなるだろうな
I'll probably be scared of
mountain passes in a year or so.
だが　峠の勘が鈍っていない今なら
But I can still engage in a reckless battle because my
sense of mountain pass driving hasn't gone numb.
まだ怖いもの知らずのバトルができる
I want to get revenge on that guy,
and graduate from the mountain pass.
あいつにリベンジして すっきり峠を卒業したい
重要なのは　ドライビングの技術じゃないんだ
Driving skills aren't important.
何処までガキになり切れるかですよ
What matters is how
immature you can become.
I didn't notice this in the dark
at night, but Mt. Fuji looks so huge.
夜は暗くて気づかなかったけど
近くで見るとでかいな富士山
赤城山とどっちがデカイですかね
Is it bigger than Akagi ?
Are you stupid ? Fuji is the
biggest mountain in Japan.
バカかてめ
富士は日本一の山だろう
はは　そっか
That's right. Anyway, it makes me
realize that we are indeed in Hakone.
でも何か実感するな
本当に俺たち来たんだな箱根に
コラ　お前ら
Hey guys, we didn't come
here for a school trip.
俺たちは修学旅行に来てるんじゃないぞ
Eat breakfast now.
早く朝飯食ってくれ
はーい
Okay !
ていうか史浩 引率の先生かよ
Hey, Fumihiro, you sound
like a teacher on a field trip.
おお　来たぞ　来たぞ
There they are. That's Project D.
プロジェクトDが
Hello, this is Fujiwara Tofu...
へい　藤原とうふ…
It's me.
俺だ
小柏
Kogashiwa...
You always call me out of the blue.
いつも忘れたころにかけてくるよな　あんたも
いつでもいけるぜ
I'm ready, so let's get started.
始めてくれ
じゃ　一本目のポジションを選んでもらえます
Well then, could you pick
your position for the first run ?
That's how we've been doing things.
今までそういうスタイルでやてきたんで
俺はどっちでもいい
It doesn't matter to me.
How about letting a coin decide ?
コインで決めるっていうのはどうだ
Heads is for the local, which is me, to be the lead, and tails is for you.
表なら地元の俺が先行
裏ならそっちだ
はあ　かまいませんけど
Sure. That's fine.
Good.
よし
裏
Tails...
決まりだな
It's decided. I'll be the chaser.
追いかけさせてもらうぜ
よーし　始めるぞ
Alright, let's begin !
またお前の息子とやるのか
A race against your son again ?
ああ　そうだ
Right. This time around,
he will definitely win.
今度は絶対勝つぞ
あいつは俺を超えて行こうとしてるんだ
He's getting better than me...
自分の意志で公道卒業して
...as he made his own decision to leave the public
road behind and entered the world of motor sports.
モータースポーツの世界に身を投じている
It's not something anyone can do.
誰にでもできるというものじゃない
His efforts brought him the chance.
努力でチャンスを掴め取ったんだ
そりゃ立派だ
Sounds wonderful.
What about your son ?
Can he surpass you ?
お前の息子はどうなんだ藤原
お前を超えられるのか
カウント行くぞ
I'm starting the countdown !
Five...
五
I'll get revenge for my loss on the Iroha Slopes.
いろは坂での借りをきっちり返す
四
Four...
三
Three...
Two...
二
One...
一
ゴー
Go !
よーし　始まった
Alright, they're off !
Go, Kogashiwa !
行け　小柏さん
Do you remember that MR-S driver, Kogashiwa ?
覚えているか　涼介
あの小柏っていうMRSのドライバー
ああ　もちろん
Of course. The guy who got pumped
up against the Emperor's Sudo, right ?
いろは坂でエンペラーの須藤につっかかってたやつだな
カートじこみのテクニックで
He drives a mid-ship car very
well, thanks to his go-kart skills.
ミッドシップをうまく扱うドライバーだよ
Who'd have thought he'd
show up in a place like this ?
こんな所で出てくるとはな
やれやれ
Looks like this's going to
be another tough battle.
ラクはさせてもらえそうにないな　今回も
啓介の相手も 現役でレースをやってるドライバーだし
Keisuke's opponent is also
an active racer, a real athlete.
本物のアスリートだぜ
確かにレースに出るドライバーは 時計のセンスが違うんだ
Right. Race car drivers
have a different sense of time.
They know how to shave it off very well.
タイムを短縮するための走り方を熟知しているってことかな
サーキットで戦うなら 勝ち目は薄いが
If we were on a circuit,
our chances would be very slim...
こっちのステージは峠だからな
...but the public roads are our stage, so
there's no need to flinch at our opponent's title.
敵の肩書きに臆することはない
We'll be able to win if each of
us carries out our job perfectly.
一人一人が自分の仕事をきっちりとこなせば
必ず勝てる
負けるバトルなら　俺は来ない
I didn't come here to lose a battle.
The car's improved.
進化しているな その車
さすがに北関東を勝ち抜いて来ただけのことはある
No wonder it kept winning
in the northern Kanto area.
だが　今の俺にはミステリアスなものなんかじゃない
But it's no longer mysterious to me.
The turning ability is simply a matter of tire capacity and load balance...
旋回性能は単純にタイヤのキャパシティと荷重バランスだし
...and acceleration is a balance
between power and weight.
加速力はパワーと車重のバランスでしかないんだ
You may be able to fool others, but not me.
他のやつはごまかせても
俺の目はごまかせないぜ
ミスをしなければ勝てる
If I don't make any mistakes, I can win.
I'll watch your progress in this first run, and finish you off in the second.
この一本目で おまえ自身の進化を見届けてから
二本目で確実にしとめてやる
You divide this course into three
sections to build an overall strategy.
今回のコースは
全体を三つに区切って攻略のイメージを作っていくんだ
上に行くと道幅が広くスピードが乗る区間
The upper section is wider for faster speed.
中間はタイトコーナーが続く超低速区間
The middle part is a super slow section with continuous tight corners.
下りてくると
And the lower part is a middle-speed section where you can
step on the gas even though the road is somewhat narrow.
道は狭いけど
そこそこアクセルをふめる中速区間といったところかな
サーキットを走るドライバーから見れば
Although circuit racers would
consider the entire course very slow...
全部が超低速セクションになっちまうんだろうが
峠はスピードのレンジが低すぎる
The range of speed is
too low in mountain passes.
もっとアベレージが高ければ
If the average speed was faster,
I could have gained a clear advantage.
差ははっきりと出せるんだが
それを言い訳にしない
But I won't use that as an excuse.
勝負所は最後のセクションだ
The last section is the decisive point.
If I were Fujiwara, I'd make my move there.
俺が藤原なら
そこで行く
Can he do that against a pro ?
可能なのかな そんなことが
プロを相手に
He has to. This is when he
has to show his true potential.
やるしかねだろう
藤原にはここらで一発
本気の底力を見せてもらわねーとな
なんとなく予感めいたものを感じるんだよな
I have this eerie feeling.
We might end up seeing it on this course.
出そうな雰囲気だぜ
このコース
See it, you mean...
ええ　出そうってまさか
勘弁してくださいよ
Oh no, I'm not really
good with those things.
俺マジでそういうのだめなんですよ
You idiot.
I never said you'd see a ghost.
バーカ
別に幽霊が出るとは言ってねーよ
インホイールリフトか
Inner wheel lift ? He's good.
うまいもんだぜ
But I doubt such artistic control
actually contributes to his speed.
だが　そこまで芸術的なコントロールが速さにどれぐらい繋がっているかは疑問だぜ
俺たちレーシングドライバーに
Race car drivers don't play around.
遊びは要らない
速いか速くないか
Faster or not, that's all that matters.
それだけだ
藤原ゾーンと兄貴は呼んでるけど
My brother calls it the Fujiwara Zone...
...but it's not exactly the same
as the ones used by top athletes.
トップアスリートがよくいうゾーンというものとはちょっと違う
藤原プラスハチロクという組み合わせで起きる現象なんだ
It's a phenomenon that only occurs
between Fujiwara and his Eight-Six.
What kind of phenomenon is it ?
どういうものなんですか
説明するのはちょっと難しい 兄貴以外はな
It's difficult to explain,
except for my brother.
I'm not so sure either.
俺にもよく分からないし
But when I drive behind Fujiwara during practice,
there are moments that catch me off guard.
プラクティスなんかで
たまに藤原の後ろについて走ってるときに
あれっと思う瞬間があって
He pulls away for some
reason that I can't explain.
理解できない車間の開き方をしてしまう
出るのか出ないのか誰にも分からない
I thought it was like a mirage.
You never know when you'll get to see it.
蜃気楼のようなものだと思うようにしてたけど
But there's a Fujiwara Zone for sure.
確かにあるんだ
藤原ゾーンは
特定の条件が揃ったときに出てくる
He shows it when a certain
set of conditions are met.
一番重要なのは
What's important is the
unique rhythm of the course.
そのコース特有のリズムなんだ
What was that ? My mistake ?
何だ今のは
俺のミスか
I can't let my guard down.
油断はできないな
忘れちゃいけない 俺は一度この男に負けているということを
Remember, I lost to him once before.
またか
Again ? He pulled away at the exit.
立ち上がりですっと離れる
俺のミスか
Was it my mistake ?
My strategy was not to make any.
ミスをしない作戦だったはず
何より気に入らないのは 俺が慌ててることだ
What bothers me most is that I'm upset.
向こうのペースに乗せられてるじゃねーのか
I might have gotten carried away by his pace.
A point where his rhythm changes ?
リズムが切り替わるポイント
そう　ポンとアクセルを踏んですぐに抜く
Yes. From a rhythmic repetition of stepping
on the gas, then releasing it right away...
リズミカルな繰り返しから少しためるリズムに変わっていく
...to a rhythm of delaying the release a bit.
今二台がいるあたりがちょうどそのポイントなんだ
The two cars are right at that point.
何かが始まるとしたらそこだな
That's where something might happen.
何かって　何が
Something ? What is it ?
藤原ゾーンがつぼにくるだろ
The peak of the Fujiwara Zone.
I've always wanted to ask you.
What exactly is it ?
前から聞きたいと思ってたんだけど
どんな種類のものなんだそれは
He didn't just start showing it recently,
he did it a long time ago.
今に始まったことじゃない
以前から確実にあったものなんだ
When I raced against him on
Akina, I caught a glimpse of it.
俺が秋名であいつとやりあったときには
もうチラホラ出現していたが
パープルシャドウと対戦したあたりから
I feel like it was refined after
he raced against Purple Shadow.
急に洗練されてきたように思う
要は
Simply put, it's his level
of training in the Eight-Six.
ハチロクという車を扱うときの 熟練の度合いというか
そういうものが藤原の場合
When it comes to Fujiwara, his level
is beyond our normal imagination.
普通では考えられないレベルにあるんだ
It must be the result of his
abnormal practice environment.
特殊な練習環境によるものだろう
前のバトルで言ってたよな
You said he heard the voice of the
Eight-Six during the previous battle.
ハチロクの声を聞いたとか
業界では人車一体という言葉をよく使うけど
In the auto industry, they often use the phrase, "The driver and the car as one"...
現実には1トン以上ある物体を
...but in reality, no one can handle
one-ton of metal as if it were their limbs.
血の通った手足のように扱える人間なんていない
だけど　藤原とハチロクのペアに限っては
But something like that happens
between Fujiwara and his Eight-Six.
それに近いことが起こるんだ
He can use the best part of the tires just
when they begin to skid whenever he wants.
タイヤがすべり出す瞬間の
一番おいしいところの出し入れが自由自在にできるし
向きを変えるスライドと前に進むスライドの切り替えが自由自在だ
He can also freely switch between the
side for turning and the slide for acceleration.
その結果どんなことが起きるかと言えば
As a result, what happens is that
the Eight-Six accelerates like a 4WD.
あのハチロクはまるで4WDのように加速する
そんなバカな
No way, that's not possible.
ありえないだろう
もちろんありえない
Of course it's not.
ハチロクはどう転んでもリアドライブだからな
The Eight-Six is still a rear-wheel drive car.
見るものにそんな錯覚をさせてしまうほど キレがいいということさ
What I mean is that the Eight-Six maneuvers
so sharply that it creates such an illusion.
後ろから見せ付けられたショックはでかいぜ 分かるやつならな
It's a huge shock to see it from behind,
especially to those who know what I mean.
同じような姿勢でコーナリングしていても
Even if you enter a corner the same way,
he points his car to the exit a moment quicker...
いちはやく車が出口を向いて
ゼロステアでアクセルを踏んで
...then he steps on the gas with zero
steering angle to accelerate earlier.
いちはやく加速態勢に入る
There is a moment when his driving style perfectly
matches the peaky characteristics of the car.
そんなドライビングのスタイルが
偶々あの車のピーキーな性格に ビシッと嵌ってしまう
今のところ俺にも
I can't completely explain it.
完全な説明はできていない
お前に説明できないことなんてあるのか
You have things you can't explain ?
あるさ
There are.
Especially things like the performance
of Fujiwara and his Eight-Six...
特に藤原とハチロクのパフォーマンスは
...can't be explained by any theory.
セオリーだけでは説明できない
Fujiwara Takumi:
Takahashi Ryosuke:
Takahashi Keisuke:
Uehara Mika:
Takeuchi Itsuki:
Iketani Koichiro:
Kenji:
Miki Shinichiro
Koyasu Takehito
Seki Tomokazu
Hayami Saori
Iwata Mitsuo
Yao Kazuki
Takagi Wataru
Kogashiwa Kai:
Kogashiwa Ken:
Omiya Satoshi
Minagawa Hideo:
Kubo Eiji:
Hojo Gou:
Fumihiro:
Matsumoto:
Kenta:
246A:
Kanna Nobutoshi
Arimoto Kinryu
Tochi Hiroki
Konishi Hiroyuki
Kase Yasuyuki
Kiuchi Hidenobu
Hosoi Hajime
Nisho Ryotaro
Okano Kosuke
Maeda Hiroki
Fujiwara Bunta:
Ishizuka Unsho
Falling perfect lighten the focal
Following the brake light of the front car.
Kurai michi no saki ni bonyari nijimu akari
暗い道の先にぼんやりにじむ明かり
It's the silence like a silent film.
If the tires strike a silent wind
A
Central Anime
Production
Translation:
Hiro-kun
Timing:
Todd Perkins
Editing:
Barbara
Todd Perkins
Brain
Dave
Mouse
Tayori ni naru mono wa sore shika mienakatta
頼りになるものはそれしか見えなかった
Kono namiki michi wo nukete ikeba kitto
この並木道を抜けていけばきっと
Tsukameru youna ki ga shita
つかめるような気がした
Get up! I just can't understand.
Give up! I just can't understand
Sokoniwa mada sagashimono wa nani mo nakute
外にはまだ捜し物は何もなくて
Yeah, it starts at this moment.
Yeah! It stops at this moment
Kono basho kara
この場所から
Please turn over the flyleaf.
Please stand alone on the flyleaf
I lost my way.
I lost my way
白く曇った窓と的外れなNavigation
Shiroku kumotta mado to
Mato hazure na navigation
Akaku kawatta shingou de
赤く変わった信号で
サイドミラーに映る視界を遮るLight
Side mirror ni utsuru shikai wo saegiru light
Tsumetai kaze ga hairikomanai youni
冷たい風が入り込まないように
窓をそっと締めたんだ
Mado wo sotto shimetanda
Get up! I just can't understand.
Give up! I just can't understand
Soko ni hirogaru michi wo erande susumu bokuwa
そこに広がる道を選んで進む僕は
Yeah, it starts at this moment.
Yeah! It stops at this moment
Kimi ga iru nana
君がいるなら
Please turn over the flyleaf.
Please stand alone on the flyleaf